<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Vladimir Kukushkin</title>
<link>https://wowone.github.io/</link>
<atom:link href="https://wowone.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Vladimir Kukushkin&#39;s personal space</description>
<generator>quarto-1.5.57</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Welcome to Journal Papers Product Minds Club</title>
  <link>https://wowone.github.io/posts/2024-10-22_Welcome/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="float-figure">
<p><img src="https://wowone.github.io/posts/2024-10-22_Welcome/Sgt_Peppers_Lonely_Hearts_Club_Band.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<p>My name is Vladimir Kukushkin. I’ve been working more than 10 years as a data analyst / data scientist. The slash sign means here that I usually deal with product analytics problems requiring data science techniques, like predictive analytics, causal inference, building statistical models, etc. In particular, I specialize in user behavior analysis a.k.a. quantitative UX research or, more general, in any sequential data analysis. Besides working on these problems as a data analyst, I played major roles in developing retentioneering open-source Python library aimig to facilitate this type of researches.</p>
<p>In my humble opinion, undeservably little attention is payed to this area. Even though such researches are quite sophisticated compared to traditional funnel or cohort analysis, a deep dive into Quant UX sheds the light onto real understanding how your product’s users behave. In particular:</p>
<ul>
<li>What drives them to churn/purchase/subscription/etc. (causal inference),</li>
<li>What clusters the users form (cluster analysis),</li>
<li>What caused some unexpected behavior that was captured by our dashboard charts (root cause analysis).</li>
</ul>
<p>And since there’s not much literature devoted to this topic, I’m going to carefully collect and review any papers, books, and publications that would seem interesting to me.</p>
<p>Just like Sgt.&nbsp;Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band has expanded the horizons of perceptions, I will be glad if this journal club attracts the attention of dat aanalysts and data scientists and helps expand their horizons too. And yes, “club” in the title means that I hope to find here some enthusiasts and discuss with them any aspects of these topics. <em> <br><br>♫ Music playing ♫<br> We’re Sgt.&nbsp;Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band<br> We hope you will enjoy the show<br> </em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://wowone.github.io/posts/2024-10-22_Welcome/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://wowone.github.io/posts/2024-10-22_Welcome/Sgt_Peppers_Lonely_Hearts_Club_Band.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
